<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>app on Brian Pfeil</title>
        <link>https://brianpfeil.com/categories/app/</link>
        <description>Recent content in app on Brian Pfeil</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 02:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brianpfeil.com/categories/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
<title>Minotes</title>
<link>https://brianpfeil.com/post/minotes/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 02:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianpfeil.com/post/minotes/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&#34;images/Icon-72@2x.png&#34; width=&#34;125px&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many choices for notes apps out in the App Store.  So many that it&amp;rsquo;d be a couple days effort just to look into and evaluate them all.  Everything from the built-in simple Notes app to the feature packed &lt;a href=&#34;http://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;.  A notes app is one of those utility apps that gets a lot of mileage like mail and weather.  Something with high usage you want the most efficient and streamlined app.  It&amp;rsquo;s also something that becomes personal and people get attached to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted something extremely simple, clean up, and fast.  I started with the simplest possible solution of a single &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UIKit/Reference/UITextView_Class/Reference/UITextView.html&#34;&gt;text view&lt;/a&gt; you could type in.  From that, the ability to create multiple notes was added, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the freedom to create as many notes as you want.  Having constraints on the number of notes forces the user to create more meaningful notes and manage / clean up notes.  The goal with minotes is not to have an archive of all historical notes with search, etc.  The type of notes appropriate for this app are short-lived ones and in general have a lifespan of around a week.  I landed on a UI metaphor similar to mobile safari with a max of 9 notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preferences around typography and text size is something that is really needed in order to be useful for more than a specific set of users.  For example, older people may need a little bit larger font size, whereas younger users may want to cram more text on the screen and are fine with a smaller font size.  In order to keep it simple, there are three typefaces to choose from and in sizes, small, medium, large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an opinionated app built with my specific needs in mind.  It&amp;rsquo;s doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to appeal to all users universally, but if you like simple purpose built apps, check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;images/1.png&#34; width=&#34;150px&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;images/2.png&#34; width=&#34;150px&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;images/3.png&#34; width=&#34;150px&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://minote.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Minotes Product Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/minotes/id648015483?ls=1&amp;mt=8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/app-store-badge-200x100.png&#34; width=&#34;125px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>